<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tring Philippe Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://philippetring.fr/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://philippetring.fr/"/>
  <updated>2016-03-13T18:25:18+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://philippetring.fr/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philippe Tring]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Don't Be Fearless]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/03/13/dont-be-fearless/"/>
    <updated>2016-03-13T18:06:06+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/03/13/dont-be-fearless</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/dont_be_fearless.jpg"></p>

<p>I read &ldquo;The End of The Night&rdquo; a book about light pollution from artificial lighting. While reading it I remember one little story from my past I was very young maybe 6-8 years old. My old brother had some friend over for the night and they were watching a horror movie. It is way too scary for me and wanted to go to sleep but the corridor was dark. I asked my brother to come with me but he and his friend made fun of me. I ended up with two choices continue watching the horror movie or go into the dark, alone to my bedroom full of my imaginary bogeyman.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>I Will Never Be Fearless</h1>

<p>I heard that all the time. Be fearless. Like nothing can stop you. Live your life to the fullest and what if I’m full of fear? Sorry but I am. I’m afraid. I’m afraid of so many things. Will my English be good enough? I am good enough? Can I do it?</p>

<p>There are two types of fear.</p>

<ul>
<li>Biological fear, it’s the one that helps us survive millions of years, that tell us to run in front of a predator and also trigger an automated step back when my mum eyebrow goes angry.</li>
<li>Rational fear, it’s the one we inflict to ourselves when we are afraid of speaking in public, basically everything we are afraid of doing when it won’t have survival consequences and mostly society education fear based.</li>
</ul>


<p>Here I’m speaking about the rational one. So please don’t try to beat the fear from falling from 20 meters high.</p>

<h1>Fear That Stop You</h1>

<p>You feel the fear right? I do too. Probably more than everyone else (at least that’s what everyone thinks !) and it sucks. So I stay here waiting for the right moment, I make excuses and soon enough follow avoidance, procrastination and insecurity. I feel like I stop living when I don’t confront my fears. We are born afraid of darkness. Light is the new norm but back in the day people had gaslight which was less brighter than today light. Even before we had fire light and at the start we had stars and moon reflection. What I mean is even physically we don’t know darkness, we are born in the light. Look I’m typing in front of a screen light by led.
I’ve never enjoyed a sky full of stars in total darkness, it’s not too late. I wasn’t born knowing how to face my fears, it’s not too late. Be hopeful don’t stop here because you hadn’t done it, it’s not too late.</p>

<h1>Fear Push You Forward</h1>

<p>If I want to live fully. I should be scared as shit of life ! Your heart should be full of doubt and fear but still taking that backpack and travelling. Still going to the unknown and confront those fears. So instead of being fearless which is totally impossible. Embrace your darkness, know yourself, your strength, your weakness, your dream, and YOUR FEAR.</p>

<p>Embrace fear. Know fear. Know that fear only is a cycle. Someday you are scared as shit then the next day you feel relieved of such a burden, nothing can stop the monster in you. Like a night which is always followed by a day. Like a yin-yang kind of thing. Nothing is permanent, everything changes, so do I.</p>

<p>Fear only exists if love exists both can’t be separate in your life. Nobody is fearless, fight your today fear will only bring bigger fear to destroy. Sometimes you’ll have to face the same fear over and over. Or being stuck in a fake artificial light (your comfort zone) away from darkness. Fear is intimidating, yet instead of having a feeling of impossible let’s be inspired, motivated even excited by it. The more I’ll face it the more I expect him to come. Eventually I can’t wait for the next day to bring his fears.</p>

<div class="iframe-responsive-wrapper">
    <img class="iframe-ratio" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhEAAJAIAAAP///wAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAQAAkAAAIKhI+py+0Po5yUFQA7"/>
    <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/F157geaXp_w" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>Embrace darkness. Like bane be moulded by your fear. You’ll be a full human when you get out of your fear and let your fear go because it belong to nothing more than your head.</p>

<h1>Fear Keeps You Out of Your Comfort Zone</h1>

<p>The moment you take your friends for granted you are doomed. Be afraid to loose them. Last night I was taking the tramway to go back home and saw someone hit at full speed by a car. Let’s not take life for granted. Hades can show up anytime</p>

<p>I wish you fear in your life a lot of it and depression too. Sounds mean? But it’s out of love. It makes you grow. Fear is an opportunity, an opportunity to grow, evolve. In fact this post was first just an entry in my journal that I rewrote for my blog. Writing down things really help even if I’m scared of how people will react. Might be helpful to someone else. You never know.</p>

<p>Best fears in your journey.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture was taken during a run session. Just ended the half marathon for the first time last week, step by step conquering my fear</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Step Back]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/23/step-back/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-23T22:47:01+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/23/step-back</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/step_back.jpg"></p>

<p>So it’s saturday night and I’m doing nothing. Like absolutely nothing. At first I was a bit empty. Like nothing is going on tonight come on I’m 23. Ain&rsquo;t I suppose to have the time of my life for god sake.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>step back</h1>

<p>It’s like a painting, if I watch it closely i’ll only see a bunch of color or maybe even a single color. But if I step back I can see the whole beauty of it.</p>

<p>So when the time come and I feel like i’m not having the time of my life. Step back and see the whole painting. On my day, my life, i’m having it. The time of my life. This moment, everything that did and do happen is awesome.</p>

<p>So now instead of stepping back from a painting what if I step back from me?</p>

<p>Because the beautiful painting I want to see is actually nobody else than me. I remember this week being upset because I was going to get in the train. When the guy just ahead of me was stepping in. He then stop moving instead of going further so people can go inside too (Please tell me that annoy you too !)</p>

<p>But that’s trying to change someone I have no direct control over. I’m trying to change something outside. But reflecting back the guy who was actually following me into the train got in the same situation as I because I was also stopping once i&rsquo;m in the train.</p>

<p>Step back and see myself as a third person because at the end that’s the thing I can change the most.</p>

<p>Now that I have step back I can judge myself according to my own belief. Would I try to be friend with myself? Would I like the painting i’m seeing (me in case you haven’t follow).</p>

<p>Once I find myself. The self I believe is good then maybe… Just maybe&hellip; I will be able to change mankind to… Kind man</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is a wall painting took at Bilbao in Spain. Imaging you zooming in the front of the shoe only. Way less beautiful, right?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vision and Goal at Lululemon]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/17/vision-and-goal-at-lululemon/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-17T14:24:32+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/17/vision-and-goal-at-lululemon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/vision-and-goals.jpg"></p>

<p>Two days ago I had the opportunity to attempt the vision and goals workshop at Lululemon.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Vision and goal</h1>

<p>Basically, you get to hangout with a lot of people who want to be a better version of themselves, you get some time to discover what’s important to you, all that in 2 hours ! They provide a set of exercices to make:</p>

<ul>
<li>You write the 8 first values that come to your mind that define you.</li>
<li>Mark them from a scale to 0 to 10 to see how driven by them you are and where you need to refocus.</li>
<li>List all the things you want and the things you don’t want in your life.</li>
<li>Visualize a day in 10 years from now with a guided meditation (which i really liked)</li>
<li>Set career, health and personal goal</li>
<li>Set goals in 10, 5 and 1 year from now</li>
</ul>


<p>So the first part vision is to make you visualize what you want while the second part are the triggers of your imagination !</p>

<p>So overall it was great. Even though I find it difficult speaking in front of so many people (I love speaking one on one but group dynamics is really something I need to work on). I would have preferred to be grouped as pair. Which would had create personal connexion between people and more involved. (It&rsquo;s also easier to confess dreams to one that to a whole assembly)</p>

<p>To find out more check the Lululemon blog
<a href="http://blog.lululemon.com/vision-goals-why-we-love-them-and-how-to-get-started/">http://blog.lululemon.com/vision-goals-why-we-love-them-and-how-to-get-started/</a></p>

<h1>What happened to me</h1>

<p>I had one big epiphany during the visualization. So here I was trying to visualize the 10 year older me. At first I saw&hellip; NOTHING… But then they ask us the question &ldquo;How do you feel in that 10 years from now day?”. My first answer was of course: Happy. Then as my eyes were close I changed the feeling from happy to peaceful.</p>

<p>Peaceful to me is the ability to keep calm and serene as the flow of moments pass. Being able to remain like water, embracing what happen and evolve to a form while still being water. Like the water shape to adapt to his context. Be me in every context or something like this (I admit it is kind of a weird concept)</p>

<p>So I want to be peaceful in 10 years from now. But as I was thinking about this something else came up, something BIG. <strong><em>Peace is already in me</em></strong>, somewhere. It won’t come from outside like having a house, money, traveling, clothes, friend, spouse. But from inside. All I need is making it blossom more and more until it became the default state. Don’t get me wrong those things are still nice to have but they are not mandatory to happiness and inne peace.</p>

<p>So what action will I do to progress toward inner peace?</p>

<ul>
<li>To the question &ldquo;how are you&rdquo; i’ll answer : “I am happy and peaceful”. This idea is inspired by Meng (<a href="http://www.mengstupiditis.com/2011/10/how-am-i-i-am-happy-and-at-peace.html">http://www.mengstupiditis.com/2011/10/how-am-i-i-am-happy-and-at-peace.html</a>)</li>
<li>Every morning i’ll practice visualizing me reacting calm to “bad” stimulus</li>
</ul>


<p>The 10 year vision is still cloudy or i’m too afraid to face it. All I can imagine is being a martial art teacher and help people having a better health.</p>

<p>My 1 year goal are pretty easy to see. I’ll be feeling the world on my bike and make a 60 seconds handstand in a year.</p>

<p>All that being said, existentialism is a dangerous thing, I need to find a balance in my thinking and action taking. Back to work, spanish podcast and handstand training time !</p>

<p>PS: That was not a sponsored post, I just love Lululemon&rsquo;s culture</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from another Lululemon event running near les quais de seine in Paris</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Values: Be Brutally Honest]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/10/honesty/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-10T16:25:33+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2016/01/10/honesty</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/value-transparence.jpg"></p>

<blockquote><p>Write down what you STAND FOR on this planet.  Find it, breathe it, live it.  If you were to die tomorrow you would know that this body, this life was not in vain as you stood for this purpose through all obstacles.  You stood ALL IN on life.</p></blockquote>

<p>This is part of my manifesto, values that I follow. Somewhere I can go to and refer in case I&rsquo;m having trouble making decisions.</p>

<p>The first value is: <strong><em>Be Brutally Honest</em></strong></p>

<ol>
<li>To me, I&rsquo;ll be courageous enough to live a life true to myself, not the life others expect of me</li>
<li>To others, I&rsquo;ll strive for an open communication by listening, understanding only then responding with honesty</li>
<li>In action, I&rsquo;ll act my words and live my acts</li>
</ol>


<!-- more -->


<h1>To me, I&rsquo;ll be courageous enough to live a life true to myself, not the life others expect of me</h1>

<p>What does it mean to be honest, real or true? True, true to myself first of all. My desires, my goals and what I really want out of this life, my life.</p>

<p>How many time I have been delusional about a situation? Hoping for the best without taking the actions to change the output. Instead taking a passive stance, waiting to see what will happen. It&rsquo;s so much easier to let thing happen. From the moment we are born until being a young adult, every things has been taken care of.</p>

<p>For most of us the first 20 years are pretty set from the beginning. Or what I mean is it doesn&rsquo;t count on us being responsible for our lives but rather our parents or whoever is responsible for us. Life will eventually flow. But then we discover a lot of things we were protected from. Like Buddha who lived peacefully in his secular place and then discover sickness, old age and death.</p>

<p>In a much smaller way for us. That moment is generally the end of school, but school doesn&rsquo;t teach us much about love, financial independence, confidence, social skills, but certainly a lot about how to be a job and fit to society. Find ONE job and keep there until retirement so we can finally take the time to do what we want.</p>

<p>So how does the brutally come from? Brutally because it takes a lot of guts to confront facts, it&rsquo;s never easy. Especially since I am born super lucky in a rich country. I shouldn&rsquo;t have anything to complain about, there&rsquo;s no bomb dropping next to my house, I have so much water that I can pee in it, and enough food to pick and refuse some of it. But being brutally honest, is it a reason to not live this life to the fullest and accept a &ldquo;safe&rdquo; life? There will be no replay to this life. So I will make the most I can of it.</p>

<blockquote><p>A free man is free to acknowledge his fears, without hiding them, or hiding from them. &ndash; The way of the superior man</p></blockquote>

<p>Most of the time it&rsquo;s social fear (and not biological one) that stop me from doing what I want. Acknowledge the fear, face it, confront it, live at his edge, then be brutal to fear, push it. Fear will never go away. I&rsquo;ll always have to fight it back. It&rsquo;s a life long war, an everyday battle. Like talking to a stranger, speaking in public, going on adventures. Basically getting in a position where I can fail will make me anxious. Even if I&rsquo;ve done it before, it&rsquo;s just less here or I simply know better how to deal with it.</p>

<blockquote><p>Build YOUR dream even if you get sidetracked helping others build theirs. Never lose sight of what YOU want. NEVER give up.</p></blockquote>

<p>I can&rsquo;t blame people for me taking the wrong direction. When facing problem do not delay them and act upfront to find a solution instead of waiting for a sign from destiny. Be responsible, I can&rsquo;t control everything that happen but I&rsquo;m in full control of how I react.</p>

<h1>To others, I&rsquo;ll strive for an open communication by listening, understanding only then responding with honesty</h1>

<p>The previous part was about being true to my inner me. But on the outer side authenticity apply aswell.</p>

<p>Tough things is: Be honest with someone, even when I know it may hurt. I mean not angry honest. I mean sincere, sensitive honest. In my view, I owe it to the person. Have a frank conversation about the other person&rsquo;s shortcomings or mine and how it impact me, tell them how I feel and do it as early as possible.</p>

<p>The benefit is that I don&rsquo;t have to think so much about what previous lie I did say. It become less of a burden overtime. It&rsquo;s hard to be honest but overall the calm in my mind is much more rewarding. Not having to think about what I said before to X to be congruent with my past lie. Not having to make 3 hours of assumptions. After a few experiment I see people reacting much better to honesty than I hoped. People are though. The ones who react in a bad way are the one who feel insecure and can&rsquo;t handle being wrong often. That also filter people I don&rsquo;t want to hang out with.</p>

<p>I also know something is wrong if I have to lie about it. Everything I do, every choices I make, I want to be proud or at least have no fear of telling them. Maybe my choices will be the wrong decision but I don&rsquo;t want to have to hide them. When I know my life ain&rsquo;t got no secrets I&rsquo;ll be more likely to make morally good decision</p>

<p>I can see a few cases where the full transparency guidelines don&rsquo;t apply. Most obvious example is if someone tell me to keep a secret, I will.</p>

<h1>In action, I&rsquo;ll act my words and live my acts</h1>

<p>Honesty also mean not saying I&rsquo;ll do something and not doing it. Saying i&rsquo;ll introduce someone to someone, I often found a pattern where I keep saying &ldquo;Oh you have to read this&rdquo;. Then I never lend the book. Everytime I&rsquo;m conscious I&rsquo;m doing that I popup evernote or calendar and add a note to remind me to do it. Do what you promise. Follow up with my words, that way i&rsquo;ll be more aware of what I say. Another benefit is I won&rsquo;t commit to things I&rsquo;m not going to do. Or be brutally honest and tell people I don&rsquo;t want to do it. But don&rsquo;t leave people wondering what will happen next.</p>

<p>Another area where it applies is being late, nowadays nobody show up on time and that&rsquo;s crazy ! Everytime someone is late I feel like he is saying my time is more precious than yours. I can make you wait for me. And the lost, what a lost ! It&rsquo;s linear, imagine a group of 7 if one of them make the rest wait 10 minutes it&rsquo;s 60 minutes lost. The more i&rsquo;m on time the more people are going to be on time because they know i&rsquo;ll be on time. But just in case always have a book ready when I wait</p>

<blockquote><p>To me ultimately martial arts means honestly expressing yourself. &ndash; Bruce lee</p></blockquote>

<p>What Bruce Lee wanted to say through this quote is that it&rsquo;s easy to do fancy martial arts move but to tell the truth is much more harder. To me it mean to don&rsquo;t make my life more shinier than it really is just to brag, be humble and not being the man who think he knows everything. Always be happy to be wrong and recognize it. I know how hard it is to step back from things that I have previously said. It&rsquo;s considerate as a sign of psychological disorder to change your mind, &ldquo;unstable&rdquo;, &ldquo;conflictual&rdquo;. But it&rsquo;s better being wrong and realizing it than being wrong and keeping your position just to maintain congruency with my past words or acts. Take my articles, I could go back and argue with a lot of them. So it makes me incongruent with my past unless I don&rsquo;t consider it as <em>my past</em> but simply <em>past</em>. An older version of me which is outdated. Would I be mad for a program bugs that were fix long ago ? No. But I would be if they were unfix bugs</p>

<p>Live my acts, that&rsquo;s taking full responsibility for previous acts. Fight for my words, but happily admit being wrong with no ego. Past will always be here. I harm people sometimes, I ain&rsquo;t proud of stuff. But be brutal and confront myself. Live your past, carry it, there&rsquo;s no escaping. Ultimately it&rsquo;s my choice to make it more heavier than it is or not&hellip;</p>

<h1>Final words</h1>

<p>I know this value has to be the first when I read the 7 habits of highly effective people. The first word that did come to mind was authenticity. Even though I knew it was it, it still took me 3 months to write it and have the courage to post. I guess I&rsquo;ve consciously delayed the writing of this value for so long for a reason. I am afraid of the consequences that this value will have to my life when I completely adopt it. I know i&rsquo;m still not totally living by honesty. The power of engagement will help me since I made a public announcement about it. When I visualize what qualities I want people to remember me for&hellip; I hope they will see me as an honest dude who asked the right question for their growth.</p>

<p>Nowadays I&rsquo;ll try my best to live this value <strong><em>Be Brutally Honest</em></strong>.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from the hitchhiking gathering near Valence in France, the little river accessible on a 30 seconds foot walk right behind a lovely bamboo forest sweet time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2015 Reflection]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/12/30/reflection/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-30T12:23:56+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/12/30/reflection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/2015-reflection.jpg"></p>

<p>2015 is almost over and I had some great epiphany during this year. I like to take some time to reflect every 3-6 month with myself, <strong>MY LIFE</strong> (and not other people vision on life). Check what have done lately, I&rsquo;m I doing the things that I must do instead of what I should do? <a href="https://vimeo.com/120355373">The Importance of Doing What You Love by Elle Luna</a></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>So I opened up my calendar to see what were my appointments</p>

<ul>
<li>The product I&rsquo;m developing at <a href="http://www.plezi.co/">plezi</a> got release, after one year of work. I can&rsquo;t help but feeling proud about it</li>
<li>I asked for a raise. Sometimes you just have to have the gut to ask</li>
<li>I said yes to a spontaneous road trip, which end up leading to Etretat and sleeping on a hill. Everyone has things to do, but I feel like life will only get more busier</li>
<li>I accomplish my first year of shiatsu and expanded my perception on eastern medicine.</li>
<li>I tried to fast during 7 days. <a href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/09/12/experience-do-not-eat-for-a-week/">Experience: Do Not Eat For A Week</a></li>
<li>I walked Camino de Santiago, also got there by hitchhiking from Paris</li>
<li>I deepen my relationship with my friends and I&rsquo;m happy to call 3 person on this universe that way. They make me a little more courageous and compassionate. Thank you</li>
</ul>


<p>It&rsquo;s also the year have been reading the most. It&rsquo;s funny how my reading have been following my grow during the year. All of this did not happen in a single day, and it&rsquo;s awesome seeing who I was a year before and who I am today.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s the light side, and it&rsquo;s fairly easy to brag about it. But on the dark side I can&rsquo;t count how many things didn&rsquo;t work this year. But the question I should ask myself is do I like my life? If not remove what makes me unhappy. Because it only takes one success to make all those experiences worth</p>

<p>That was a lot of I. Your turn:</p>

<ul>
<li>Reflect on your last year and celebrate achievements then share them with whoever you want</li>
<li>Ask yourself what makes you unhappy and remove it this year</li>
</ul>


<p>Ps: I just wrote a <a href="http://philippetring.fr/now">now</a> page which list what i&rsquo;m up to. Where is my focus, <a href="http://philippetring.fr/now">check it out</a>.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from the most beautiful city on earth, Paris ! Near les quais de la Seine</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Face Writing Block]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/12/face-writing-block/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-12T19:21:25+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/12/face-writing-block</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/face-writing-block.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> How to face writing block? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I missed yesterday OPAB. Usually when I miss something. I stop, instead of being persistant. That&rsquo;s funny because the day before I was super in the flow for writing. I don&rsquo;t know how it feel from the exterior but creating everyday is crazily hard. You have to always push yourself and deny every good excuse that come your way (being tired, don&rsquo;t having the time).</p>

<p>And one of my block was that I was only doing all my challenges for myself. So if I don&rsquo;t write who cares really? Nobody knew. But now with the blog every one might.</p>

<p>So how can I prevent failling? I can&rsquo;t it will eventually happen. But I can at least minimize the amount of energy it takes me to start writing.</p>

<p>It mean 2 things for now. Always having a pen and some paper (I want to buy a &ldquo;moleskine&rdquo; really badly haha). And having my computer ready to write every time.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from a beach in Montpellier. That is creativity !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Do I Breath?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/10/value-one/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-10T11:38:41+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/10/value-one</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/value-relationship.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> Values one: Why do I breath? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I can&rsquo;t wait to start this article. I am so excited to start writing about it. I was literally in the transport with no paper left and tons of ideas were flowing through me. Think i&rsquo;m also half wasted which hasn&rsquo;t happen for years. Just to warn you when i&rsquo;m drunk I tend to tell everybody I love that I do love them (my little sister and mother just had me hugging them for quite a while&hellip; With all my after sport session odor of course).</p>

<p>Before start I need to share 2 things&hellip; No 3 things. I had training (that&rsquo;s one), got myself beat a few times as usual much respect to all my sparing partners and it was incredible. Two we had a few drink but more important a lot of laugh (I couldn&rsquo;t stop smiling during my one hour of commute back home). Three.. I forgot 3 might come back might not.</p>

<p>That being said after all my previous speech on happiness I think I have a pretty good answer to what&rsquo;s happiness to me. <strong>It&rsquo;s building long lasting relationship with people I do care about</strong>. Let them teach me a lot of thing and do my best to have a positive impact on them. It&rsquo;s making them smile and share no&hellip; SHARE moment with them. Lately i&rsquo;m pretty introverted. I tend to focus on myself, &ldquo;be a better version of me&rdquo;. But for who? For me. And that&rsquo;s obviously not working. My mood and attitude got lower. I&rsquo;m the best me only when i&rsquo;m with those people who move me. Those people I hate but also love.</p>

<p>Some of them are ALWAYS ******** late, some are messy as crazy. But I still love being with them. And so happy to see them when the last time have seen them was only 2 weeks ago. Hope they will recognize themselves !</p>

<p>I do remember number three !! Happiness, I was so happy commuting back home, I took a bicycle at the last km. And I haven&rsquo;t feel that great biking since&hellip; Going on my Paris to London on a bike trip. I was aware of the wind, my legs and foot pushing the bike, I was here not going from point A to B just here, living the moment. I am so use to forget about my journey, only focussing on my destination that I&rsquo;m always skipping the now. Which is as important as the moment I arrive at the point B.</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s my first value? What is the first thing I want to stand for in my life? <strong>Grow as an independent being and help people I care about grow</strong>. My memory will disappear soon enough after my last breath, my money won&rsquo;t serve me anymore, my stuff won&rsquo;t last forever but if I did exist for those few people I&rsquo;ll be done here. I might not change the world but I do hope I&rsquo;ll change their world.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Talking about stuff, one of the fine lady at the dojo make me realize how much have changed since she knows me (2 years ago). I was a stuff oriented guy, always with a new dress. Now I only have 2 pants and 3 t-shirts, is it good? Probably not for everybody but for me at this moment it is. And that&rsquo;s what matter, living on my belief. Picture is me 2 years ago</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Values]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/09/values/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-09T17:05:08+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/09/values</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/values.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> On happiness? part 2 </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Had no problem today so i&rsquo;ll just continue on my questioning on happiness. Last time I said happiness is already in me. Maybe all I need to do is let it express itself? My mum gave me a mini handy book about buddhism few weeks ago. After my research it seems that we need to drop everything or at least this is the goal as a buddhist. (I might miss interpret i&rsquo;m far from an theologist on buddhism).</p>

<p>But looking to have no attachment material and/or emotional we can&rsquo;t loose right? We can&rsquo;t be sad because we already have nothing? But a life with no attachment is it really a life?</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s one of the thing that do scare me. Since I live on nothing today (I&rsquo;m talking about money / cost of life) it&rsquo;s easy to go on adventure with nothing. But will I have the courage to drop my comfy flat once I get use to it? I read a experiment in &ldquo;Stumbling on Happiness&rdquo;. People were offered 60k first year then 50k then 40k OR 30k then 40k then 50k. People always choose the second option regardless of the obvious gain in money to take the first choice.</p>

<p>That&rsquo;s probably also related to the fact that we want to see progress in our lives and can&rsquo;t stand to be demolish in a way or another.</p>

<p>But at the same time if I decide to attache myself to nothing and nobody I&rsquo;ll get jealous about other people possession, I want the last iPhone too ! So I need to neglect other people but it&rsquo;s so human to compare me / my possession with other people. Think people who reach that state, being egoless non toxic and self confident must have something else. A belief that what they do is right. and since i&rsquo;m not sure my way is the right way i&rsquo;m stuck.</p>

<p>What I need to work on to let my happiness blossom is my believe, not in god but what do I believe my values are. So instead of comparing myself with other I&rsquo;ll be able to compare myself with my values. I have few ideas for my values. But had never took the time to write about it properly.</p>

<p>I like the way this challenge make me wonder about life. Really, don&rsquo;t know if what I say is accurate or even make sense but&hellip; Yeah whatever.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is a dog name Tao I had the opportunity to be licked by him at the hitchgathering this year.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Things I Can Do When Bored]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/08/things-i-can-do-when-bored/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-08T19:25:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/08/things-i-can-do-when-bored</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/to-do-when-bored.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> What can I do when i&rsquo;m bored? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>That&rsquo;s pretty funny given all the things I can do in life that we achieve being in a state of bored no? Is being bored something that animals feel or only humans? Ok let&rsquo;s come up with 10 things I can do.</p>

<ol>
<li>Write anything on anything. You never know what you might come up with</li>
<li>Send a message to somebody you want to meet. Or better call an old acquaintance</li>
<li>Take some time to breathe</li>
<li>Make a to do of what I need to do before leaving</li>
<li>Run / exercice</li>
<li>Read</li>
<li>Clean my room / organize my stuff. I think the act of organizing physically something have the same effect on your mind somehow !</li>
<li>Wow it start to be hard after 7&hellip; Cook? (I usually never cook)</li>
<li>OH I HAVE A GOOD ONE ! Ask myself if i&rsquo;m heading to the right direction for my life.</li>
<li>Do something, anything but do something.</li>
</ol>


<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is the red moon of this yearg</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Invent Problems]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/07/how-to-invent-problem/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-07T18:39:51+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/07/how-to-invent-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/how-to-invent-problem.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> How to invent problem? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>How am I suppose to find a solution to nothing. My problem of the day is that I had no problem. (huhu)</p>

<p>Think that&rsquo;s a good reminder that people who looks for trouble can always find some. But honestly today have been great. Had a yoga session at Lululemon (This company is great) and it was free ! Then I walked back home exploring streets of Paris I&rsquo;ve never seen before. Family launch, few videos, few mails and some paper I had to fill. Then at night I run almost an hour to see an old friend of mine back from London. Played some board game like a child and met a lot of interesting people.</p>

<p>Basically i&rsquo;ve learn a lot today ! Will I remember that day as a great day? Maybe if I read this article one day who knows</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture was taken near New Haven in UK while waiting for the boat. I can still remember the wild blackberry taste I had miam !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Make the Most Out of School?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/06/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-school/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-06T13:24:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/06/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-school</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/how-to-make-the-most-out-of-school.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> How to make the most out of school? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Guess I&rsquo;ve done nothing at school today, I procrastinate taking everything in my reach to don&rsquo;t work. So what can I do to make the most of this time I have to spend here?</p>

<p>Start a business on the side. To create wealth or value as passive income, visibility, sharpens skill that will matter lately. But knowing that everything can be learn. Choosing the right field to invest my time on is blocking me: paradox of choice, having too much abundance make me stuck. Pick something whatever and do something.</p>

<p>Does everything I learn need to be useful thought? I know not but I can&rsquo;t stop blaming myself not being &ldquo;productive&rdquo;. Yesterday I spoke about happiness and how the Bhutan check for growth in happiness. <strong>With mathematics started the era of numbers when older people use to have different metrics</strong>. Without number, productivity, marks and other metrics life must have been so different. We want proof that it works before starting anything nowadays (This apply so much to me, HOLY MOLLY !)</p>

<p>But I&rsquo;m going off topic here, back to school. (I actually smiled when writing this haha). Skills and career out. I think school is before everything else the best time to connect to people, thing that I don&rsquo;t do enough. Proof, I&rsquo;m here typing on a keyboard talking to nobody but myself while I could be exchanging with people made of blood and heart next to me.</p>

<p>Maybe I focus way too much on myself. Maybe I should change the challenge from &ldquo;fix one problem I have during my day&rdquo; to &ldquo;help someone fix his problem&rdquo;? But who am I to help someone. People didn&rsquo;t ask for anything. But I do ask myself for help right here.</p>

<p>Another thing is that I focus too much on the future me. I should relax&hellip; No I&rsquo;ll relax. There is no rush for me to start traveling I want everything and right now. Why the rush? Put your belt and enjoy your journey through school. I know lot of people miss that time after it&rsquo;s over.</p>

<p>Lastly to make the most out of school I shouldn&rsquo;t focus on the reward (the degree). But on what I&rsquo;m learning. And what do I learn here? The degree do not mean I made it, right? Take the number to change, how many of us will have no suitable jobs? What I learn at school is simply to learn for the rest of my life.</p>

<p>Philippe, student of life hopefully I&rsquo;ll never drop out.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is the school from the village I used to live back in Bangladesh</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Be Happy?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/05/how-to-be-happy/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-05T15:16:24+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/05/how-to-be-happy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/how-to-be-happy.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> How to be happy? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Ok, how should I start that hard question it might seem too optimist to answer this question for everyone so I&rsquo;ll try to solve it for me. What&rsquo;s happiness? Is it me watching a youtube video, eating awesome food, laughing hard with my friend, having sex, being rich? All that is pleasure for sure and does bring happiness for a short instant but in the long term wont bring sustainable source of happiness. What&rsquo;s the common denominator for all of these things? They come from outer world instead of my inner self. Does eating more or that will make me forever happy? Having multiple partner for intercourse, a higher salary, all those numbers. I heard Bhutan is calculating happiness grow in their country. I wonder how they do that.</p>

<p>In the old time when math doesn&rsquo;t exists life must be so much different. We are now numbers everywhere. Of like, share, salary&hellip; So if I follow the hypothesis that happiness come from inside and not outside. How can it be ?</p>

<h1>How can I speak about happiness without speaking about sadness? One doesn&rsquo;t exists without the other.</h1>

<p>If happiness cannot exists without sadness then two solutions come to my mind.</p>

<ol>
<li><p>I can only be happy if someone else is sad ?</p></li>
<li><p>I can only be happy for a determined amount of time until sadness come back to me.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I don&rsquo;t like the first option because I hope everybody can be happy (shameless way to put it out of the way haha).</p>

<p>If happiness and sadness are both natural state. It make me realize that being happy is already a possibility in me. If that&rsquo;s the case how can I be more happy than sad and more importantly recover from sadness to be back to a happy state? Well I have no clue but right now I want to go to the dojo and practice martial art.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from Etretat in the morning. Funny that i&rsquo;m searching for complex reason about happiness when maybe sustainable happiness is achievable simply by bringing attention to one’s breath.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Much Money Is Enough]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/04/how-much-money-is-enough/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-04T17:45:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/04/how-much-money-is-enough</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/how-much-money-is-enough.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: <strong> How much money do I need to live? </strong></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;m starting to realize that in a few months I won&rsquo;t hang out in Gobelins anymore (My school). Will I miss it? Probably not. I&rsquo;m bored and can&rsquo;t wait for what&rsquo;s next. But what&rsquo;s next? I have no clue. I&rsquo;m searching for path, possibilities. The most appealing one is to travel around the world like a hobo. But it&rsquo;s also the scariest one. So I&rsquo;m looking for a job and I start asking myself what&rsquo;s a good job? I see plenty of my developer friend who after a few months in a well paying job stop it to pursue an uncertain path to grow a business and i&rsquo;m very impress by them. So money is not the problem, people don&rsquo;t want to be rich we want the possibilities that offer money.</p>

<p>At 2k money I can live more than enough. So here&rsquo;s my number, how can I make it for the least amount of time so I can enjoy life the rest. Here&rsquo;s one of adult life goal, having 2k of income each month for the less amount of work (Work: Time I dislike the use of).</p>

<p>This lead naturally to tomorrow problem. How do I get happy?</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture are my feet after a cloudy day of hiking in the mountain of Spain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OPAB: How to Respond to Violence?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/03/respond-to-violence/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-03T17:02:35+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/03/respond-to-violence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/violence.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: How to respond to violence?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>People in my class bought some Nerf (Plastic gun) to battle in the classroom. Then for fun one of them aimed his gun toward me&hellip;</p>

<p>Edward, a Bagua (Form of Tai Chi) practicer once told me there&rsquo;s 3 way to react from an aggression:</p>

<ol>
<li>Freeze. It can be because you are afraid but also simply because you hope the predator won&rsquo;t see you like a butterfly or ostrich</li>
<li>Flight. Run, as fast as you can avoid, dodge the threat !</li>
<li>Fight. Put your arms up and be brave</li>
</ol>


<p>Guess what I did in front of this Nerf pointing at me? Did I fight, flight or freeze? I freeze, put my hands up to hide my face and did nothing else hoping he&rsquo;ll not shoot. Ok he was my friend and I knew nothing so bad would happen.</p>

<p>Another time I was biking in Paris when a car hit me at slow speed but I catch myself and keep rolling. The man get out of his car and start yelling at me. In my head confident in my few years of martial art training I thought he deserved a lesson but I kept rolling and I&rsquo;m very happy I did.</p>

<p>So what&rsquo;s the point of all my practice in the dojo? Being ashamed of myself because I can&rsquo;t respond to violence? I think it&rsquo;s worth it for me to freeze and run even if I have a pretty good chance to win a fight. First harming someone doesn&rsquo;t feel good, I can live with a bit of shame I&rsquo;d rather not break anything. I also preserved the good relationship I have with my friend. I think the only time I&rsquo;ll need my martial art skill is to fight for someone else or my life. It&rsquo;s the last choice and there&rsquo;s nothing to be ashamed if you run or lower your head.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from the top of a castle in India</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OPAD: How to Remember Anyone Name?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/02/remember-them/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-02T17:20:58+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/02/remember-them</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/remember.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo;. Where I have to solve a problem I have through my day. Today: How to remember people?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Today I had to lend Getting Things Done the book to a classmate boyfriend. But I forgot the name and had to say &ldquo;Hey give that to your honey&rdquo;. Well I&rsquo;m almost 23 and have already a hard time remembering people name, im getting old&hellip; That&rsquo;s why today I created a system ! It&rsquo;s called&hellip; Badaboum&hellip; Drum sound&hellip; Well, I don&rsquo;t know the name of it yet. Any suggestion?</p>

<h1>The system</h1>

<p>Everytime i&rsquo;ll meet a new person can be anyone, the guy from the supermarket to the neighbour. i&rsquo;m going to put it on my evernote note called &ldquo;People Reminder&rdquo;. Just the name and few details that might or might not be relevant. Simple, clean, not sophisticate&hellip; Like me ! (except the clean part)</p>

<p>I do hope that this will pay in the long run. And even if it doesn&rsquo;t it&rsquo;s worth the try. Obviously most of the people on this list. I&rsquo;ll never meet again but it will be so powerfull when socializing and the weirdo I am need to compensate somewhere.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is a guy this summer who was running instead of walking on camino de santiago. I run with him during a day when it was raining like never before. It was awesome but I ended in a hospital the next day ! I can&rsquo;t match a name with his face&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[OPAD: How to Face Depression?]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/02/smile/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-02T00:05:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/11/02/smile</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/smile.jpg"></p>

<p>This article is a part of my 30 days challenge &ldquo;One Problem A Day&rdquo; where I have to solve a problem each day. Today: How to face depression ?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Heck I didn&rsquo;t feel like starting this month challenge. I had the most unproductive week end ever, watched my computer all week and slept. Think I had this unproductive 2 days because I didn&rsquo;t wanted to face my life problem ! It was so much easier to lay on my bed all day instead of deciding what I want to do with my life. Take this job opportunity with lot of skills I can learn or discover the world. Just the thought of it already give me a headache.</p>

<p>So what can I do when I feel like shit? The answer came while watching One Piece with my little sister. A giant named Saul have an awkward laugh &ldquo;Deshishishi&rdquo; and he teach a little girl to smile even when life is apparently bad. So here I was in front of my mirror with my one minute timer set, laughing at myself, trying to replicate him. Which ended being hilarious !</p>

<div class="iframe-responsive-wrapper">
    <img class="iframe-ratio" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhEAAJAIAAAP///wAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAQAAkAAAIKhI+py+0Po5yUFQA7"/>
    <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/-TrSNqBKmpA" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>~~~</p>

<p>The picture is from Bilbao in Spain after 5 days of hiking through Camino de Santiago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WebGL Workshop at Gobelins]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/10/16/webgl-workshop-at-gobelins/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-16T13:54:25+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/10/16/webgl-workshop-at-gobelins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/three-js-experimentation.jpg"></p>

<p>We had a 4 days workshop at <a href="http://www.gobelins.fr/">Gobelins</a>, having fun making 3D and animation. You can see the result at <a href="http://philippetring.fr/Three-js-experimentation/" title="Three js experimentation">http://philippetring.fr/Three-js-experimentation/</a></p>

<p>For the inspiration the first part is a Spoken Word (a form of poetry) originally perform by Prince EA. The second part is from Matrix, the movie.</p>

<p>Let me know what you think in the comments, criticism more than welcome.</p>

<p><a href="http://philippetring.fr/Three-js-experimentation/" title="Three js experimentation">http://philippetring.fr/Three-js-experimentation/</a></p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture is from the experiment itself</p>

<!-- more -->

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Experience: Do Not Eat for a Week]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/09/12/experience-do-not-eat-for-a-week/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-12T19:34:21+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/09/12/experience-do-not-eat-for-a-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/fasting.jpg"></p>

<p>Recently I tried not to eat for a week. In my attempt the rules were simple. I could only drink water, tea, and sparkling water.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Why did i try to fast for a week?</h1>

<p>We were sitting with one of my friend planning our 30 days challenges of the year when he told me about water fasting. He told me about the benefit for the body allowing it to recover and giving it enough time to get rid or the toxins. He shook some of my belief about food and the way we consider our food. I also had heard about Ghandi fasting for what he believed and my mom had a lot of no food days back in her days. All I needed was someone to push me trying it for myself.</p>

<h1>How it goes?</h1>

<p><strong>First day (Thursday)</strong> was interesting at around 10 o’clock i was super hungry. I think my mind knew he was going to starve so I was hungrier than usual. After a power nap instead of usual meal I was fine. Bed time and going to sleep made me realize not eating for a day was actually much more easier than I thought.</p>

<p><strong>Second day (Friday)</strong> I had an epiphany… Not having to think about what I’m going to eat is such a freedom. You don’t start wondering what your meal is going to be ! It’s impressive how much my mind is thinking about food on a regular day.</p>

<p><strong>Third day (Saturday)</strong> was easy despite not being as busy as I am at work. I even get to go to my martial art class at Parc de la Villette with no impact on me. (Maybe my teacher was going easy on me because he knew i was fasting). At night I realized food was also a social connector. Most of the time I hang out in restaurants, bars, or whatever. It’s just a good reason to meet with my friends.</p>

<p><strong>Fourth (Sunday)</strong> day was terrible i’ve done nothing but laying on my bed all day and skipped classical dance class (lot of classy here !). It was also the day that I gave up on the fast, at night I couldn’t sleep and when I walked to my restroom my balance was so messed up that I felt on to the ground. I texted my friend who inspired me to do the fast and told me it was all right (I felt guilty leaving him alone). But before eating that pineapple in the fridge I made a quick video to remember how I felt. (It wasn’t supposed to go public so don’t be shy and enjoy seeing me half naked)</p>

<div class="iframe-responsive-wrapper">
    <img class="iframe-ratio" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhEAAJAIAAAP///wAAACH5BAEAAAAALAAAAAAQAAkAAAIKhI+py+0Po5yUFQA7"/>
    <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/byy_QoxyRMw" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen></iframe>
</div>


<h1>Now come the time to reflect.</h1>

<p>I really get a chance to think back on food. Might sound obvious but I’m grateful to have food in my plate whenever I want. This line doesn’t make justice to the way this experience made me have a new look at food. Think it’s kind of like love, faith, being angry those are things someone need to experiment in order to know it.</p>

<p>Food is everywhere and I did spend a lot of time thinking about it on <strong>3 main fields</strong>:</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>Time</strong>,
I waste so much time thinking about food. What I’m I going to eat today? Question start at 11am. Then the same at night. All this time spending making decision is time and energy not available to think about what really matter.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Health</strong>,
Is this good for my health? I feel guilty eating too much. Eating junk too much. As my friend said:</p></li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>We are what we eat.</p></blockquote>

<ul>
<li><strong>Money</strong>,
Well this one don’t bother me. I don’t care paying a lot to eat good stuff. It’s not about the money itself but the way industry appeal me to buy always more food. The more you buy the less you spend for the amount I have. Then I end up eating more food of usually bad food. It’s just not working in the right direction. Now I know I don’t need to eat that much to live.</li>
</ul>


<p>So now that I know all that what I’m I going to do?</p>

<ul>
<li>Stop eating when i’m bored and do 5 minutes relaxation instead (Replace with something you find pleasure in)</li>
<li>During eat time. Stop when I feel 80% full (Pareto law).</li>
<li>Deny free food if I’m not hungry.</li>
<li>Stop taking the food that has the most quantity and think in terms of quality.</li>
<li>Avoid plain sugar</li>
</ul>


<p>Food on a less conscious state is also a lot of other things. An entertainment, an object of pleasure, I got food when I’m bored, when I’m depressed, when I socialize, when I spend money (a lot of money), when I have sex (sometimes), as a gift, as an addiction, as a huge part of economy, as a diet, as a reward…
During the fast I had progressively all those field getting back at me. At first I wanted to eat food to distract me, then because my friend were going to eat, then at the end because I was hungry. Back to the basic, the fundamental. Food is my body essence.</p>

<p>Thanks to Ali for his help writing this and inspiring me to make this wonderful experience.</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>Picture has been taken on a improvised hitchhiking trip week end at Etretat.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Culture Asiatique]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/06/08/culture-asiatique/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-08T00:05:27+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/06/08/culture-asiatique</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/culture-asiatique.jpg"></p>

<p>La famille dans laquelle on grandit est responsable d&#8217;une grande partie de notre futur nous. Quand je regarde les habitudes de notre société occidentale et celle des traditions amenées par la culture orientale transmis par mes origines. Je comprends mieux le mal que j&#8217;ai à m&#8217;acclimater parfois.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Je prends comme exemple les repas, car c&#8217;est le moment qui réunit une famille, le rite. La chose que j’aime le plus est dans le partage de la nourriture à la maison. 2/3 des repas consiste en un buffet ou tout le monde se sert à son gré. Contrairement aux repas occidentaux où chacun à son plat et se l&#8217;approprie.</p>

<p>D&#8217;un autre côté, mes parents ayant connu la famine célèbrent tout par la nourriture. Mon grand frère qui revient samedi aura probablement le plat qu&#8217;il souhaite. À nos anniversaires nous avons le choix de la nourriture plutôt qu&#8217;un choix de cadeau.</p>

<p>La seconde chose qui m&#8217;interpelle est la conversation. La plupart de nos repas sont pleins de blanc. De silence, les enfants apprennent à écouter avant de parler. Merci Confucius. Ce qui n&#8217;est pas mal, mais demande une réadaptation par la suite.</p>

<p>Enfin sur les couverts. Nous utilisons des baguettes au lieu de couteau et fourchette. C&#8217;est une jolie métaphore, celle de la non-violence. Lorsque l&#8217;on pique et coupe, d&#8217;autres transportent la nourriture avec délicatesse et respect exerçant uniquement la force nécessaire afin de maintenir la denrée le temps du transport.</p>

<p>Finalement, la part des choses est à faire une fois adulte. Que garder et quoi enlever? La perfection étant lorsqu&#8217;il n&#8217;y&#8217;a plus rien à enlever. La vie c&#8217;est peut-être ça au final. Au départ, nous sommes tous vides puis nous nous remplissons soit d&#8217;eau pure, claire, bonne ou d&#8217;eau malsaine, impure. Parfois, nous arrêtons de nous remplir ou renversons de l&#8217;eau. Enfin, notre eau peut toujours être éclaircie ou polluée. Nous sommes les seuls à pouvoir décider de la contenance de notre conteneur.</p>

<p>Qu&#8217;est ce que je vais faire aujourd&#8217;hui pour rendre mon eau plus claire et me remplir aujourd&#8217;hui ?</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>La photo a été prise près de Montpellier. Au lac du Salagou ! Une eau pure?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[S'immerger Dans Une Culture]]></title>
    <link href="http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/06/04/simmerger/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-04T18:44:16+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://philippetring.fr/blog/2015/06/04/simmerger</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="http://philippetring.fr/images/simmerger.jpg"></p>

<p>Ma petite soeur rentre aujourd&#8217;hui d&#8217;un voyage scolaire de 5 jours en Angleterre. J&#8217;ai très hate qu&#8217;elle me raconte ses aventures. Et me demande a quelle point sont anglais s&#8217;est amélioré. Pourquoi s&#8217;immerger dans une culture?</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>J&#8217;ai fait le voyageur touriste en Inde en visitant de multiples monuments. Du cyclo tourisme en Angleterre. En habitant et aidant les locaux Au Bangladesh. Cet été j&#8217;esseyerais en marchant. S&#8217;immerger dans une culture est pour moi devenu très important. Car je pense que c&#8217;est le seul moyen de &ldquo;sentir&rdquo; le pays. Le premier pas est de parler la langue puis de repérer les traditions enfin d&#8217;y prendre part. Comme faire le ramadan au Bangladesh. Aucun n&#8217;ai néanmoins la meilleur façon de voyager, chacun ont leurs avantages</p>

<blockquote><p>Si j&#8217;agis comme un touriste les gens me prendront comme un touriste.</p></blockquote>

<p>Comment agissez vous en voyage?</p>

<p>~~~</p>

<p>La photo est prise au Bangladesh, je me lavais les pieds en portant un loungi, vêtement typique et très confortable !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
