<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bike | Gnirt's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://Gnirt.github.io/blog/categories/bike/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Gnirt.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-01T03:10:01+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://Gnirt.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Philippe Tring]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Liste Pour Une Balade en Vélo]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gnirt.github.io/blog/2014/08/01/liste-pour-une-balade-en-velo/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-01T02:00:51+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gnirt.github.io/blog/2014/08/01/liste-pour-une-balade-en-velo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/list_items_bike.jpg"></p>

<p>Hello étant donné que j'avais déjà dans un fichier texte avec la liste toute prête, je partage avec vous la liste de ce que je ramene avec moi pour ce voyage de <strong>1 mois en vélo</strong> au Royaume-Uni !</p>

<!-- more -->


<h3>1. Sacoche sur le porte bagage :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Ortlieb Back Roller Plus : 40 litres</li>
</ul>


<h3>2. Vêtement :</h3>

<ul>
<li>1 Chaussure de running</li>
<li>3 paires de chaussettes</li>
<li>1 Paire de tongs</li>
<li>1 Jeans résistant (peut être retroussé pour en faire un short)</li>
<li>1 Sarouel hyper soft et comfortable</li>
<li>1 Maillot de bain</li>
<li>3 boxers</li>
<li>1 Sur pantalon étanche de golf (C'était moins cher)</li>
<li>1 Débardeur</li>
<li>1 T-shirt</li>
<li>1 Veste polaire chaude</li>
<li>1 Veste étanche en Gore Tex</li>
<li>1 Gant étanche pour faire la vaiselle (Jaune car c'est classe !)</li>
<li>1 Lunette de soleil</li>
</ul>


<h3>3. Matériel de bivouac :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Hamac</li>
<li>Couverture de survie</li>
<li>Sac a viande</li>
<li>Sac de couchage 10°C</li>
<li>Boussole</li>
<li>Lampe frontale à pile</li>
<li>Bento</li>
<li>Cuillère</li>
<li>Thermos (Pour l'eau)</li>
<li>Couteau</li>
<li>Couteau suisse</li>
</ul>


<h3>4. Toilette :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Serviette microfibre</li>
<li>Brosse à dents</li>
<li>Dentifrice</li>
<li>Papier toilette</li>
<li>Gel antiseptique pour les mains</li>
</ul>


<h3>5. Outillage :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Démontes pneus</li>
<li>Pompe à main</li>
<li>Clé allen</li>
<li>Chambre à air</li>
<li>Rustine</li>
</ul>


<h3>6. Electronique :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appareil photo numérique</li>
<li>Téléphone portable</li>
<li>Adaptateur prises</li>
<li>Clé USB</li>
</ul>


<h3>7. Divers :</h3>

<ul>
<li>Journal de bord (pour avoir un souvenir !)</li>
<li>Le livre <em>Les quatres accords toltèques</em></li>
<li>Stylos</li>
<li>Carte routière</li>
<li>Sac réutilisable (Autant être écolo jusqu'au bout !)</li>
<li>Sacoche (Pour garders mes papiers important sur moi en toutes circonstance)</li>
<li>Des chouchous (pour attacher mes cheveux)</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jumping on My Bike and Rolling [En]]]></title>
    <link href="http://Gnirt.github.io/blog/2014/08/01/jumping-on-my-bike-and-rolling/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-01T01:27:05+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://Gnirt.github.io/blog/2014/08/01/jumping-on-my-bike-and-rolling</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="center" src="/images/bike_uk.jpg"></p>

<p>Hey guys! As some of you may know this summer I decided to do a roadtrip during <strong>1 month on my bike alone to United Kindgom</strong> going as far as i can (without injuring myself of course!)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Actually im leaving my house in few hours but decided to simply make a quick post to share my plans with all my dear fellas ! You might wonder, why am I writing in english today?</p>

<p>Well I really need to improve my english and especially my writing skills. By the way if anybody answer this post and find let&rsquo;s say&hellip; 5 errors in the text, I Philippe TRING swear to take him/her to get a drink ! But I also have a few (but really loved) friends who doesn&rsquo;t read french. Back to the topic here&rsquo;s the plan.</p>

<h1>Date</h1>

<ul>
<li>Departure : 1 august 2014 from Paris.</li>
<li>Return date : 31 august 2014 at Paris. (I&rsquo;ll try not to be late and not to skip first day of school, but can&rsquo;t promise it mommy !)</li>
</ul>


<h1>My path :</h1>

<p>Going from Paris to Dieppe (north of France) then taking the boat. That&rsquo;s as far as my current roadmap show ! Then taking the boat to Newhaven. When landing, first thing get a roadmap of UK.</p>

<p>Then I actually have 4 ideas in my mind depending on how much time do I have left.</p>

<ol>
<li>If I have plenty of time, going to Scotland get a sweet 20 years old whisky (Heard it was sweet ! Maybe an alcohol I finally enjoy ?)</li>
<li>If I have soso of time going to Ireland ! Find a leprechaun, take a selfie with him.</li>
<li>If I have a short amount of time going to the New Forest National Park. Camp some days then go back.</li>
<li>Finally, if I have very few days left go to London. Find a crowded place sing/dance and try to get at least 10 dollars !</li>
</ol>


<h1>FAQ</h1>

<p>How are you going to deal with [insert random statement] ?</p>

<blockquote><p>I believe that we consumme to much energy and time thinking about problem that will never actually happen. When a problem actually happen i&rsquo;ll face it and let me say <strong>There&rsquo;s no such thing as problems, there&rsquo;s only solutions</strong>. Don&rsquo;t take this assumption wrong, I actually did prepare a bit before I get on my bike and go, but sometimes overthinking just kill me. Let&rsquo;s go out of my comfort zone and see what happen ! Even if i&rsquo;m a bit afraid (Probably why I can&rsquo;t sleep even if it&rsquo;s very late !)</p></blockquote>

<p>What are you going to do when you are not biking ?</p>

<blockquote><p>This year i started taking ninjutsu class (Martial Art, I know kinda cliche for an asian to do martial art AND be in CS ! Huehue). So every morning i&rsquo;m going to take 1-2 hours to stretch (things that i already do every morning but only 15 min, one day i&rsquo;ll post a picture of me doing a split !) but also doing the <a href="http://lmgtfy.com/?q=goshin+tai+so">Goshin tai so</a> as my master taught me ! <br> Then finding a shop to buy food, finding a good spot to put my hamac for the coming night. Look at some gorgeous view (Hopefully !) and finally LIVE right here right now ! (Into the wild style !)</p></blockquote>

<p>Ok, that&rsquo;s it for now, almost 3 am in the morning didn&rsquo;t plan to stay that late when i started this post ! But the good thing is I am the one who decide when the train is leaving tomorrow huehue. <strong>I am the master of my fate, I am the captain of my soul &ndash; Invictus.</strong></p>

<p>If you have any questions, comments and remember if anybody answer this post and find 5 errors in the text, I Philippe TRING swear to take him/her to get a drink !</p>

<p>Bonus : The <a href="/blog/2014/08/01/liste-pour-une-balade-en-velo/">full list</a> of what i&rsquo;m bringing with me during my trip. Peace !</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
